HARSHIL DARJI

San Jose, CA | harshilbharatkumar.darji@sjsu.edu

🗘 harshil-darji in harshil-darji 📓 highdef4k 🚨 harshil-darji.github.io 📞 +1(510)-977-2089

Summary

I am a passionate full-stack developer and a cloud-enthusiast. I love working on new projects and like to contribute to open source. I have experience in building cross platform desktop applications and also have a knack for Machine Learning. I am a determined team player with a zeal that drives me to learn new things enabling me to adapt to new technologies quickly.

EDUCATION

• Master of Science in Computer Engineering | GPA: 3.7

San Jose, CA

San Jose State University

Jan. 2021 - Aug. 2022 (expected)

Related coursework: Data Science, Enterprise Software Technologies, Cloud computing

• Bachelor of Technology in Information and Communication Technology

Ahmedabad, Gujarat Aug. 2016 – May 2020

 $Ahmedabad\ University$

Related coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Embedded Systems, Database Systems

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Javascript, Typescript, C, C++, Python, Java

Web Technologies React, Redux, NodeJS, RESTful APIs, GraphQL, Angular

Cloud Technologies Firebase, Docker, Amazon Web Services, Serverless

Databases MongoDB, Elasticsearch, MySQL, Redis

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

• React Developer ReactJS. Redux $Honeycomb\ Softwares\ Pvt.\ Ltd.,\ Ahmedabad,\ India$

Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Jan. 2020 - June 2020

- Implemented custom React components for an Enterprise Resource Planning Jewellery application.
- $\circ\,$ Integrated memoized selectors for all React components to get filtered data from state object, improving performance of components by a factor of 30%.
- o Refined and debugged several reducers to achieve efficient update of state objects.

• Web Developer Intern

Angular, Typescript, ElectronJS, Python

OpenCV, YOLO, Darknet, Tensorflow

Shunyeka Systems Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India

o Designed and built the administrator website and REST APIs to accomplish efficient user and query management.

- Developed two cross-platform Desktop applications to monitor cloud metrics of end users.
- Setup Wazuh file integrity monitoring for many servers, to alert users on changes to specified files.

• Machine Learning Intern

Bhaskaracharya Institute For Space Applications and Geo-Informatics

May 2019 - July 2019

- Engineered a video analytics software which helps to extract general analytical information.
- Processed videos to perform object detection, object counting, number plate recognition, motion detection.

PROJECTS

• Ubereats Clone | Github

MERN, Redis, GraphQL, Redux, Kafka, AWS

- Developed a food delivery platform using MERN stack, facilitating restaurants and customers.
- Reduced latency by 10% using GraphQL with optimal data pooling in MongoDB to support multiple connections.
- Configured message queue middleware to support concurrent 10k user requests.

• Flixnet | Github

React, Redux, Firebase, Stripe

- Built a movie catalog application similar to Netflix that allows users to authenticate, search and rate movies.
- Users could subscribe to different Flixnet plans configured through Stripe payments.

• Indeed Clone | Github

MERN, Docker, MySQL, Redis, Kafka, AWS

- Developed a microservices based distributed application that supports all major job board functionalities.
- Integrated features like job search, job application, chat, company reviews, facilitating job seekers and employers.
- Improved throughput of requests through caching, along with message broker middleware for improvised scalability.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

• Helped organise various technical events, talks and workshops as Technical Committee Head, IEEE Student branch at Ahmedabad University (2016-2019).